export const md_elements_coaching = [
    {
        choices: ["Straight line formula", "Euler&amp;amp;#39;s formula", "J.B. Johnson&amp;amp;#39;s formula", "Secant formula"],
        correctAnswer: "Straight line formula",
        question: "Which of the following column formulas is applicable to cast iron columns?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Isometry", "Orthotropy", "Anistropy", "Isotropy"],
        correctAnswer: "Orthotropy",
        question: "Which of the following is a material description referring to unique properties in three mutually perpendicular planes?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Lower deviation", "Tolerance", "Fundamental deviation", "Upper deviation"],
        correctAnswer: "Fundamental deviation",
        question: "This is either the upper or the lower deviation, depending on which is closer to the basic size. How do you call this deviation?                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Arc welding", "Brazing", "Riveting", "Soldering"],
        correctAnswer: "Brazing",
        question: "This is a metal joining process which uses a non-ferrous filler metal with a melting point below that of the base metals but above 800F. how do you call this process?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Whole Depth", "Space width", "Backlash", "Circular Pitch"],
        correctAnswer: "Backlash",
        question: "This minimum distance is measured between the non-driving side of a tooth and the adjacent side of the mating tooth. It is the amount by which the width of a tooth space exceeds the thickness of the engaging tooth measured on the pitch circle. What is this distance?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Self locking in both directions", "Self energizing", "Self locking in one direction", "Any of these"],
        correctAnswer: "Self locking in one direction",
        question: "In braking, the term back stop refers to a brake that is:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Hydrodynamic lubrication", "Boundary lubrication", "Hydrostatic lubrication", "Elastohydrodynamic lubrication"],
        correctAnswer: "Hydrodynamic lubrication",
        question: "This is a lubrication condition where non-conformal surfaces are completely separated by lubricant film and no asperities are in contact. How do you call this lubrication condition?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Elasticity", "Plasticity", "Conformability", "Embeddability"],
        correctAnswer: "Conformability",
        question: "It is the ability to deform plastically to compensate for irregularities in bearing assembly. How do you call this?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Working depth", "Space width", "Whole depth", "Addendum"],
        correctAnswer: "Whole depth",
        question: "This radial distance in gear is measured between the addendum and dedendum circle, and is the sum of the addendum and the dedendum? How do you call this distance?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Gray cast iron", "White cast iron", "Malleable iron", "Nodular cast iron"],
        correctAnswer: "Nodular cast iron",
        question: "This iron is also known as a ductile cast iron. How do you call this iron?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Jib crane", "Tower crane", "Overhead crane", "Gantry crane"],
        correctAnswer: "Jib crane",
        question: "How do you call a fixed crane consisting of a supported vertical member from which extends a horizontal swinging arm carrying a troelly hoist or other hoisting mechanism?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["G02", "G04", "G01", "G03"],
        correctAnswer: "G04",
        question: "In CNC programming, which of the following G code commands is for dwell or rest?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Wrought steels", "Low carbon steels", "Tool steels", "Medium carbon steels"],
        correctAnswer: "Wrought steels",
        question: "These are steels most widely used for engineering materials. No other material offers comparable versatility for product design.                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Bevel gears", "Worm gearings", "Helical gears", "Spur gears"],
        correctAnswer: "Bevel gears",
        question: "These are gears with teeth formed on conical surfaces and are used mostly for transmitting motion between intersecting shafts. how do you call these gears?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Protractor", "Sine bar", "Compound rest", "Micrometer"],
        correctAnswer: "Sine bar",
        question: "This is used either for very accurate angular measurements or for locating work at a given angle; is used together with precision gage blocks. what is this?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Paris Power Law", "Manson-Coffin Relationship", "Goodman Rule", "Miner&amp;amp;#39;s Rule"],
        correctAnswer: "Miner&amp;amp;#39;s Rule",
        question: "This is a theory in a cyclic and impact loading, which states that damage at any stress level, is proportional to number of cycles. What is this theory commonly called?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Its ductility is improved", "Its BHN becomes greater", "Its strength is increased", "Its % reduction or elongation is reduced."],
        correctAnswer: "Its ductility is improved",
        question: "Which of the following information is FALSE regarding steel that has increased carbon content?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Tolerance", "Allowance", "Basic size", "Deviation"],
        correctAnswer: "Tolerance",
        question: "What is the difference between the maximum and minimum size limits of a part?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Centro is a point in one body which another body tends to turn.", "Centro is a point in one body about which another body actually turns", "Centro is a point common to two bodies having the same velocity.", "Centro is a point in one body about which another body does not rotate."],
        correctAnswer: "Centro is a point in one body about which another body does not rotate.",
        question: "Which of the following is not true for an instant center or centro of planar linkages?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["High carbon steel", "Low carbon steel", "Cold rolled steel", "Medium carbon steel"],
        correctAnswer: "Low carbon steel",
        question: "What is the general description for mild steel?                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Allowance", "Tolerance", "Basic Size", "Deviation"],
        correctAnswer: "Tolerance",
        question: "What is the difference between the maximum and minimum size limits of a part?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Principal shear stress", "Principal normal stress", "Maximum shear stress", "Bending and shear stresses"],
        correctAnswer: "Principal normal stress",
        question: "What is the combination of applied normal and shear stresses that produces maximum principal normal stress or minimum principal normal stress, with a third principal stress between or equivalent to the extremes?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Major diameter", "Mean diameter", "Minor diameter", "Stress diameter"],
        correctAnswer: "Major diameter",
        question: "How do you call the diameter of the imaginary cylinder that bounds the crest of an external thread and the roots of an internal thread?                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Deflection", "Pitch", "Coil clearance", "Lead"],
        correctAnswer: "Coil clearance",
        question: "This refers to the space between adjacent coils when the spring is compressed to its operating length.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["SAE 3130", "SAE 1020", "SAE 6150", "AISI 301, 1/4 hard stainless steel"],
        correctAnswer: "SAE 1020",
        question: "If stiffness is the main criterion in selecting a material, which of the following is the most economical choice?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Freudentein&amp;amp;#39;s Law", "Grashof&amp;amp;#39;s Law", "Coriolli&amp;amp;#39;s Law", "Gubler&amp;amp;#39;s Law"],
        correctAnswer: "Grashof&amp;amp;#39;s Law",
        question: "&amp;amp;quot;For a planar four-bar linkage, the sum of the shortest and the longest lenths cannot be greater than the sum of relative rotation between two members.&amp;amp;quot; How do you call the preceding statement?                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["2.4D to 3.5D", "Depends on the shaft diameter", "1.25D to 2.4D", "0.5D to 1.25D"],
        correctAnswer: "1.25D to 2.4D",
        question: "In the design of key, the typical hub lengths are in accordance with the following relation where D is the shaft diameter.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Copper", "Steel", "Aluminum", "Cast iron"],
        correctAnswer: "Aluminum",
        question: "The variable polarity plasma arc (VPPA) process was developed for welding metals that form an oxide skin, such as ____________                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["12", "16", "18", "10"],
        correctAnswer: "10",
        question: "Stainelss steels generally contain at least ___ per cent chromium, with or without other elements.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Annealing", "Stress Relieving", "Normalizing", "Tempering"],
        correctAnswer: "Normalizing",
        question: "Steel is heated to a temperature above the critical range, after which it is cooled in still air to produce a generally fine pearlite structure. The purpose is to promote uniformity of structure and properties after a hot-working operation such as forgin or extrusion. What was the heat treatment involved?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Higher feed rates", "Lengthened tool life", "Higher cutting accuracy", "Higher cutting speeds"],
        correctAnswer: "Higher cutting accuracy",
        question: "Machining operations with the proper application of a cutting fluid generally has the following attributes except: ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Octahedral shear-stress theory", "Energy distortion theory", "Maximum principal stress theory", "Maximum shear-stress theory"],
        correctAnswer: "Octahedral shear-stress theory",
        question: "Von Mises theory is the other term used for",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Thermal conductivity", "Electric Resisivity", "Coefficient of thermal expansion", "Toughness"],
        correctAnswer: "Coefficient of thermal expansion",
        question: "It is a measure of the change in length of a material subjected to a change in temperature. How do you call this property of material?                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Endurance stress", "Ultimate stress", "Design stress", "Yield stress"],
        correctAnswer: "Design stress",
        question: "How do you call the level of stress that the part will be permitted to see under operating conditions?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Drag-link mechanism", "Double-rocker mechanism", "Crank-rocker mechanism", "Triple-rocker mechanism"],
        correctAnswer: "Drag-link mechanism",
        question: "It is a Grashof four-bar mechanism in which the shortest link is the frame or fixed link and the other two cranks compleete rorate with their axes. How do you call this Grashof four-bar mechanism?                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Tip", "Handle", "Tang", "Relief"],
        correctAnswer: "Tang",
        question: "How do you call the flattened end of a shank, and intended to fit into a driving slot in the socket?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Third Law", "Universal Gravitation", "Second Law", "First Law"],
        correctAnswer: "Third Law",
        question: "Newton&amp;amp;#39;s law of motion that describes that if a force acts to change the state of motion of the body, the body offers a resistance equal and directly opposite to the force.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Carbon steel", "Wrought iron", "Cast iron", "SAE 4140"],
        correctAnswer: "Wrought iron",
        question: "Which of the following ferrous metals has the lowest carbon content?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Lubrication", "Hydrodynamics", "Hydrostatics", "Tribology"],
        correctAnswer: "Tribology",
        question: "The study of lubrication, friction and wear of moving or stationary parts is known as:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Bearing", "Shaft", "Key", "Pulley"],
        correctAnswer: "Bearing",
        question: "It is a macine member that supports another part that rotates, slides, or oscillates in or on it.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Nitriding", "Tempering", "Shot blasting", "Peening"],
        correctAnswer: "Shot blasting",
        question: "How do you call the process of producing the residual compressive stress of machine parts, which is performed by directing the a high velocity stream of hardened balls or pellets at the surface to be treated.                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["One-half", "Two-thirds", "Three-fourths", "One-fourth"],
        correctAnswer: "Three-fourths",
        question: "Flywheel arms are usually of elliptical cross-section, the strength of the arms should equal _________ the strength of the shaft in torsion.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Pitch Angle", "Dedendum Angle", "Face Angle", "Addendum Angle"],
        correctAnswer: "Addendum Angle",
        question: "In a straight bevel gear, how do you call the angle between an element on the pitch cone and an element on the face con?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Tempering", "Stress Relieving", "Normalizing", "Annealing"],
        correctAnswer: "Stress Relieving",
        question: "This process reduces internal stress, caused by machining, cold working, or welding, by heating thes teel to a temperature below the critical range and holding it there long enough to equalize the temperature throughout the piece.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Interfacing", "Interference", "Fretting corrosion", "Wear"],
        correctAnswer: "Fretting corrosion",
        question: "This refers to a loss of material from the interface of two metal surfaces that are in intimate contact. How do you call this?                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Thrust bearing", "Guide bearing", "Journal bearing", "Clearance bearing"],
        correctAnswer: "Guide bearing",
        question: "A bearing that primarily guides the motion of a machine member without specific regard to the direction of the load application.                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Bending loads", "Concentrated loads", "Combined loads", "Distributed loads"],
        correctAnswer: "Bending loads",
        question: "How do you call a load that is applied transversely to longitudinal axis of member?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Sulfur", "Nickel", "Chromium", "Cobalt"],
        correctAnswer: "Sulfur",
        question: "A free-cutting steel has a higher _____ content that comparable carbon steels.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Elastic material bonded coupling", "Flexible toroidal spring coupling", "Flexible disk coupling", "Flexible Oldham coupling"],
        correctAnswer: "Flexible Oldham coupling",
        question: "A coupling that allows axial flexibility/movement in the operation. Made of alternate bolting of steel, leather, fabric and/or plastic material into two flanges.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Lathe holder", "Swivel head", "Shaper Vise", "Parallel bars and hold down bars"],
        correctAnswer: "Shaper Vise",
        question: "This is the most common work holding device of a shaper machine with the base graduated in degrees that make it possible swivel any angle. What is this working device?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Machine", "Mechanism", "Engine", "Linkage"],
        correctAnswer: "Machine",
        question: "This is a combination of mechanisms and other components that transforms, transmits, or uses energy, load, or motion for a specific purpose. How do you call this?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Addendum circle", "Base circle", "Pitch circle", "Root circle"],
        correctAnswer: "Pitch circle",
        question: "How do you call the circle on a gear that corresponds to the contact surface of the friction wheel?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Cycle time", "Tool life", "Wear duration", "Life cycle"],
        correctAnswer: "Tool life",
        question: "This is defined as the cutting time to reach a predetermined wear, called the tool wear criterion.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Stainless steel spring wire", "Music wire", "Oil tempered spring wire", "Hard drawn spring wire"],
        correctAnswer: "Music wire",
        question: "This is the most widely used of all spring materials for small springs operating at temperatures up to about 250 degrees F. It is tough, has a high tensile strength, and withstand stresses under repeated loading.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Vanadium", "Titanium", "Molybdenum", "Tungsten"],
        correctAnswer: "Titanium",
        question: "A material of construction (only developed commercially in the late 1940&amp;amp;#39;s concurrently with zirconium) offers the unique combination of wide ranging corrosion resistance, low density, and high strength.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Square key", "Pin key", "Barth key", "Flat key"],
        correctAnswer: "Square key",
        question: "A type of key in which width and thickness are equal is called as:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Any of these", "Plus or minus 5%", "Plus or minus 10%", "Plus or minus 20%"],
        correctAnswer: "Plus or minus 20%",
        question: "At certain speedsd called the critical speeds, a rotating shaft will become dynamically unstable and the resulting vibrations and deflectionscan result in damage not only to the shaft but to the machine of which it is a part. At what percentage of the critical speed should a shaft be safely operated?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Mechanical System", "Expert system", "System of mechanism", "Design system"],
        correctAnswer: "Mechanical System",
        question: "It is defined as synergistic collection of machine elements; synergistic because as a design it represents an idea or concept greater than the sum of the individual parts. What is this system?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Secant formula", "Lame&amp;amp;#39;s equation", "Euler&amp;amp;#39;s formula", "J.B. Johnson&amp;amp;#39;s equation"],
        correctAnswer: "Lame&amp;amp;#39;s equation",
        question: "Which of the following equations/formulas does not belong to the group?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Spindle diameter", "Distance between centers", "Swing", "Chuck diameter"],
        correctAnswer: "Swing",
        question: "In a lathe machine, it is the diamater of the largest workpiece it can rotate in a chuck or between centers without hitting the bed.                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["CIM", "MDI", "FMC", "FMS"],
        correctAnswer: "MDI",
        question: "An acronym in CNC machining which means access of the machine operator to insert machining instructions directly into the NC machine control system via push buttons, pressure pads, knobs, or other arrangements.                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Expansion fit", "Any of these", "Shrink fit", "Force fit"],
        correctAnswer: "Shrink fit",
        question: "This is a type of fit that requires heating the hub to expand its inside diameter. What do you call this type of fit?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Martensitic grades", "Ferritic grades", "Any of these", "Austenitic grades"],
        correctAnswer: "Austenitic grades",
        question: "What grades of stainless steals are nonmagnetic in the anneald condition, although some may become slightly magnetic after cold working?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Dynamic seal", "Distored seal", "Gasket", "Vibratory seal"],
        correctAnswer: "Dynamic seal",
        question: "This is a type of seal used where some form of relative motion occurs between rigid parts of an assembly.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Design", "Theorem", "Synthesis", "Analysis"],
        correctAnswer: "Design",
        question: "It is called as the transformation of concepts and ideas into useful machinery. What is this?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Biaxial or Plane Stress", "Strain plane", "Octahedral plane", "Principal normal stress"],
        correctAnswer: "Biaxial or Plane Stress",
        question: "What is a condition where one surface is comparatively free of stress?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Numerical method of analysis", "Finite element analysis", "Fault free analysis", "Synthesis"],
        correctAnswer: "Finite element analysis",
        question: "It is a computational method used for solving complex shapes, such as those found in machinery; replaces the complex shape with a set of simple elements interconnected at a finite set of specific purpose. what is this computational method?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Drawbar springs", "Torsion springs", "Leaf springs", "Garter springs"],
        correctAnswer: "Leaf springs",
        question: "These springs are made from one or more flat strips of brass, bronze, steel or other materials loaded as cantilevers or simple beam.                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Chrome silicon", "Chrome vanadium", "Hard-drawn wire", "Oil-tempered wire"],
        correctAnswer: "Chrome vanadium",
        question: "This material is the most popular allloy spring steel for conditions involving higher stresses that can be used with the high-carbon steels and for use where fatigue resistance and long endurance are needed; this is also good for shock and impact loads.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Anodizing", "Tempering", "Case hardening", "Normalizing"],
        correctAnswer: "Case hardening",
        question: "This is a hardening treatment for steels having low carbon content",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["200 ksi", "75 kis", "150 ksi", "300 ksi"],
        correctAnswer: "150 ksi",
        question: "A steel has a BHN = 300. What is its approximate ultimate strength in ksi?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Standard", "law", "Code", "Theroem"],
        correctAnswer: "Standard",
        question: "What is a set of specification for parts, materials, or processes intended to achieve uniformity, efficiency, and a specified quality?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Oil-tempered wire", "Chrome silicon", "hard-drawn wire", "Chrome vanadium"],
        correctAnswer: "Chrome vanadium",
        question: "This material is the most popular alloy spring steel for conditions involving higher stresses that can be used with the high-carbon steels and for use where fatigue resistance and long endurance are needed; this is also good for shock and impact loads.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Fault free analysis", "Finite element analysis", "Failure analysis", "Random analysis"],
        correctAnswer: "Failure analysis",
        question: "How do you call a statistical data used to identify the most likely failure modes?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Inertia", "Section modulus", "Momentum", "Kinetic energy"],
        correctAnswer: "Inertia",
        question: "What is the property of matter that causes it to resist any change in its motion or state of rest?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Conrad bearing", "Crown bearing", "Cylindrical bearing", "Angular-contact bearing"],
        correctAnswer: "Conrad bearing",
        question: "How do you call a ball bearing with race containing pronounced groove for rolling elements?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["MOdified Mohr theory", "Coulomb-Mohr theory", "Tresca Yield Criterion", "Von Mises Criterion"],
        correctAnswer: "Tresca Yield Criterion",
        question: "What is the other term for the Maximum-Shear-Stress Theory, as a failure prediction theory?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Non-conformal surfaces", "Sliding surfaces", "Conformal surfaces", "Rolling surfaces"],
        correctAnswer: "Non-conformal surfaces",
        question: "These are surfaces that do not conform to each other very well as in the rolling-element bearings.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Stiffness", "Rigidity", "Toughness", "Resilience"],
        correctAnswer: "Toughness",
        question: "What is the ability of the material to absorb energy up to fracture?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Carbon", "Chromium", "Sulfur", "Cobalt"],
        correctAnswer: "Sulfur",
        question: "What is an element added to steel to improve its machinability?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Contouring", "Roughing", "Angular Cutting", "Finishing"],
        correctAnswer: "Roughing",
        question: "This is a shaper operation, which is shaping the given stock and having the excess material remain with a tolerableallowance for finishing. How do you call this operation?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Polishing is any operation performed with wheels having abrasive glued to the working surfaces", "The terms & amp; amp; quot; polishing& amp; amp; quot; and & amp; amp; quot; buffing & amp; amp; quot; are sometimes applied to similar classes of work in different plants.", "Buffing is done with wheels having the abrasive applied loosely", "Polishing is not so harsh an operation as buffing, and it is commonly utilized to obtain very fine surfaces having a & amp; amp; quot;grainless finish & amp; amp; quot;."],
        correctAnswer: "Polishing is not so harsh an operation as buffing, and it is commonly utilized to obtain very fine surfaces having a & amp; amp; quot;grainless finish & amp; amp; quot;.",
        question: "Which of the following statements is NOT true?                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Cyclic load", "Bending load", "Combined load", "Distributed load"],
        correctAnswer: "Distributed load",
        question: "What is a load distributed over an entire area?                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Any of these", "Soldering", "Brazing", "Welding"],
        correctAnswer: "Brazing",
        question: "Use of hard solders, silver solders, and smelter solders which have silver, copper, or nickel bases and have melting points above 800 degrees F. is known as ______.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Symmetrical with the engineering stress - strain curve", "The same as the engineering stress strain curve", "Lower than the engineering stress - strain curve", "Higher than the engineering stress - strain curve"],
        correctAnswer: "Higher than the engineering stress-strain curve",
        question: "The true stress-strain curve in a stress-stress diagram appears to be:",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Tolerance", "Upper deviation", "Lower deviation", "Fundamental deviation"],
        correctAnswer: "Lower deviation",
        question: "What is the algebraic difference between the minimum limit and the corresponding basic size?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Thermal-shock failure", "Quenching", "Thermal fatigue", "Honing"],
        correctAnswer: "Thermal-shock failure",
        question: "When a hot part is cooled suddenly by quenching, there is a momentarily a high temperature gradient that induces a stress gradient. Some metal parts under certain conditions crack as a result. How do you call this phenomenon?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Manifest danger approach", "Fault free analysis approach", "Fail-safe design approach", "Redundancy approach"],
        correctAnswer: "Fail-safe design approach",
        question: "It is a design approach where no catastrophic loss can occur as a result of a component failure. What is this design approach?                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["G02", "G00", "G01", "G03"],
        correctAnswer: "G00",
        question: "Which of the following G-codes refers to rapid traverse in CNC machining?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Arc ratio", "Speed ratio", "Contact ratio", "Gear ratio"],
        correctAnswer: "Contact ratio",
        question: "In gearing, this is the ratio of the arc of action to the circular pitch.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Modified Mohr theory", "Maximum-shear-stress theory", "Internal friction theory", "Distortion-energy theory"],
        correctAnswer: "Maximum-shear-stress theory",
        question: "It is a failure prediction theory, which states that a part of subjected to any combination of loads will fall (by yielding or fracturing) whenever the maximum shear stress exceeds a critical value. How do you call this failure prediction theory?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Reaming", "Boring", "Milling", "Drilling"],
        correctAnswer: "Boring",
        question: "This is a machining process for producing internal straight cylindircal surface or profiles, with process characteristics and tooling similar to those for turning operations. What is this machining process?                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Strain", "Elongation", "Stress", "Deformation"],
        correctAnswer: "Strain",
        question: "It may be defined as the displacement per length producingin a solid and as the result of stress. How do you call this?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["18% nickel and 8% chromium", "18% bronze and 8% vanadium", "18% chromium and 8% nickel", "18% chromium and 8% phosphor bronze"],
        correctAnswer: "18% chromium and 8% nickel",
        question: "Which of the following are the compositions of stainless steel 302?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Strength", "Ductility", "Cold formability", "Durability"],
        correctAnswer: "Cold formability",
        question: "These steels (SAE Steels 1006, 1008, 1010, 1015) are the lowest carbon steels of the plain carbon type, and are selected where -______ is the primary requisite of the user.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Stainless steel", "Carboloy", "Stellite", "Copper"],
        correctAnswer: "Stellite",
        question: "This is the trade name for patented alloy made up chiefly of cobalt, chromium, and tungsten in varying proportions. What is this trade name?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Tempering", "Shot blasting", "Nitriding", "Peening"],
        correctAnswer: "Peening",
        question: "It is a process that produces residual compressive stress on the machine part, which uses a series of hammer blows on the surface.                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["MIG", "EDM", "CNC", "GMAW"],
        correctAnswer: "EDM",
        question: "It is an acronym in machining. This process uses an electrode to remove metal from a workpiece by generating electric sparks between conducting surfaces.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Drip lubrication", "Recirculated lubrication", "Oil stream lubrication", "Bath lubrication"],
        correctAnswer: "Oil stream lubrication",
        question: "It is a lubrication for roller chains wherein the lubricant is supplied by a circulating pump capable of supplying the chain drive with a continuous flow of oil inside the chain loop evenly across the chain width and directly at the slack strand.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Maximum size", "Basic size", "Minimum size", "Nominal size"],
        correctAnswer: "Basic size",
        question: "How do you call the size to which limits or deviations is assigned and is the same for both members of the fit: it is the exact theoretical size?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Two-point cutting tool", "Single-point cutting tool", "Grinder", "Multi-point cutting tool"],
        correctAnswer: "Multi-point cutting tool",
        question: "How do you call a cutting tool that has two or more cutting edges as in drill presses and milling machine cutters?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Cyaniding", "Case hardening", "Nitriding", "Carburizing"],
        correctAnswer: "Nitriding",
        question: "The steel part is heated to a temperature of 900-1150 degrees F in an atmosphere of ammonia gas and dissociated ammonia for an extended period of time that depends on the case depth desired.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Helical gears", "Bevel gears", "Hypoid gears", "Planetary gears"],
        correctAnswer: "Hypoid gears",
        question: "This are gears used to connect shafts taht are non-intersecting and non-parallel. They are a cross between spiral bevel gears and worm gears.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["80% improvement on the endurance strength", "Improvement of endurance strength, more than 50 % ", "Improvement of endurance strength, less than 50 % ", "Improvement of endurance strength, 50 % or more"],
        correctAnswer: "Improvement of endurance strength, 50% or more",
        question: "Which of the following is the benefit in using nitriding as a surface-hardening process for alloy steels?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["6 inches basic diameter, 32 threads per inch, coarse thread", "Size 6, 32 threads per inch, fine thread", "Size 6, 32 threads per inch, coarse thread", "32 inches basic diameter, 6 threads per inch, coarse thread"],
        correctAnswer: "Size 6, 32 threads per inch, coarse thread",
        question: "For an American Standard Screw Threads, what does 6-32 UNC designate?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Ductility", "Resilience", "Rigidity", "Toughness"],
        correctAnswer: "Resilience",
        question: "It is the capacity of material to absorb energy when it is deformed elastically and then, upon unloading, to increase this energy. What is this capacity of material?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Modulus of roughness", "Modulus of resilience", "Modulus of rigidity", "Modulus of elasticity"],
        correctAnswer: "Modulus of resilience",
        question: "How do you call the strain energy per unit volume required to stress a material from an unloaded state to the point of yeilding?                                    ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Interference", "Tolerance", "Allowance", "Clearance"],
        correctAnswer: "Clearance",
        question: "This is a general term that refers to the mating of cylindrical parts such as bolt or a hole; it is used only when the internal member is smaller that the external member. How do you call this?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Injection molding", "Forging", "Blow molding", "Extrusion"],
        correctAnswer: "Extrusion",
        question: "What is a manufacturing process used for the production of aluminum?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Conformal surfaces bearing", "Sliding-element bearing", "Non-conformal surfaces bearing", "Rolling-element bearing"],
        correctAnswer: "Rolling-element bearing",
        question: "A bearing where surfaces are non-conformed and motion is primarily rolling; it composed of rolling elements interposed between an outer ring and inner ring.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Journal Bearing", "Rolling Contact Bearing", "Thrust Bearing", "Sliding Contact Bearing"],
        correctAnswer: "Sliding Contact Bearing",
        question: "It is a bearing that permits constrained relative motion of rigid parts; lubricant is generally inserted or supplied between the mating surfaces to reduce friction and wear, and to carry away the heat generated.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Ball and roller bearings", "Any type of gears", "Flat belts and other belt types", "Journal bearings"],
        correctAnswer: "Ball and roller bearings",
        question: "AFBMA is an acronym for an association involved in what machine elements?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Quenching", "Shot blasting", "Peening", "Nitriding"],
        correctAnswer: "Nitriding",
        question: "It is a surface-hardening process for alloy steels in which the material is heated to 950F in a nitrogen atmosphere, typically ammonia gas, followed by slow cooling.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["SAE 1095", "SAE 1020", "SAE 1045", "AISI 6150"],
        correctAnswer: "SAE 1045",
        question: "Which of the following steels does not readily respond to heat treatment?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Theroem", "Code", "Standard", "Law"],
        correctAnswer: "Code",
        question: "This is a set of specifications for the analysis, design, manufacture, and construction of something; the purpose of which is to achieve a specified degree of safety, effeciency, and performance or quality. How do you call this set of specifications?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["One fourth of the shaft diameter", "One third of the shaft diameter", "One half of the diameter", "One eight of the shaft diameter"],
        correctAnswer: "One fourth of the shaft diameter",
        question: "To ensure an adequate factor of safety in the design of a shaft with standard keyway, the key width should be about: ",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["M06", "M04", "M10", "M03"],
        correctAnswer: "M10",
        question: "In CNC programming, which of the following M code commands is for a tool change?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Combined load", "Bending load", "Distributed load", "Cyclic load"],
        correctAnswer: "Bending load",
        question: "It is a load applied transversely to longitudinal axis of member. How do you call this load?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["at slow cutting speeds", "at high cutting speeds", "that are too hard", "that are too soft"],
        correctAnswer: "at high cutting speeds",
        question: "The primary application of high-speed steel is to tools used for the working of metals ________.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Boundary lubrication", "Hydrostatic lubrication", "Hydrodynamic lubrication", "Elastohydrodynamic lubrication"],
        correctAnswer: "Hydrodynamic lubrication",
        question: "This is a lubrcation where the load-carrying surfaces of the bearing are separated by a relatively thick film of lubricant, so as to prevent metal-to-metal contact; and where the stability of the film can be explained by the laws of fluid mechanics. How do you call this type of lubrication?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Annealed", "Tempered", "Quenched", "Killed steel"],
        correctAnswer: "Killed steel",
        question: "If the steel is strongly deoxidized by the addition of deoxidizing elements, no gas is evolved, and the steel is technically called ________ because it lies quietly in the molds.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Normal speed", "Variable speed", "Average speed", "Critical speed"],
        correctAnswer: "Critical speed",
        question: "How do call the speed at which a rotating shaft becomes dynamically unstable?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Dynavar", "Inconel", "Monel", "Elinvar"],
        correctAnswer: "Dynavar",
        question: "This alloy (nickel, iron, chromium, cobal is a non-magnetic, corrision resistant material suitable for sub-zero temperatures and temperatures up to about 750 degrees F., provided that torsional stress are kept below 75,000 pounds per square inch. it is precipitation-hardened to produce hardnesses of 48 to 50 Rockwell C and is used in watch and instrument springs.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["M03", "M06", "M05", "M04"],
        correctAnswer: "M03",
        question: "An M-code which generally refers to start spindle rotation in a clockwise direction.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Surface grinding", "Broaching", "Finishing", "Buffing"],
        correctAnswer: "Buffing",
        question: "A final operation to improve the polish of a metal and to bring out the maximum luster",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Aluminum", "Copper", "Manganese", "Magnesium"],
        correctAnswer: "Magnesium",
        question: "Which of the following is the lightest of all structural metals?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Failure condition", "Salvage condition", "Fail-safe condition", "Critical condition"],
        correctAnswer: "Failure condition",
        question: "It is the condition of a machine element when it is completely inoperable, cannot perform its intended function adequately, or is unreliable for continued safe use. What do you call this condition?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Limestone", "Coke", "Flux", "Slag"],
        correctAnswer: "Limestone",
        question: "The principal raw materials used in steel making are iron ore, coal and _________.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Tolerance", "Lower deviation", "Fundamental deviation", "Upper deviation"],
        correctAnswer: "Upper deviation",
        question: "What is the algebraic difference between the maximum limit and the corresponding basic size?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Machinability", "Hot hardness", "Toughness", "Elasticity"],
        correctAnswer: "Hot hardness",
        question: "This property designates the steels resistance to the softening effect of elevated temperature.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Beam", "Cantilever beam", "Column", "Overhanging beam"],
        correctAnswer: "Beam",
        question: "How do you call a structural member designed to support loads perpendicular to its longitudinal axis?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["1/4", "1/16", "1/32", "1/8"],
        correctAnswer: "1/16",
        question: "Rivet holes are made usually ___ inch larger in diameter than the nominal diameter of the rivet.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Hydrogen gas", "Nitrogen gas", "Ammonia gas", "Carbon dioxide"],
        correctAnswer: "Ammonia gas",
        question: "Which of the following gases is typically used in nitriding process of surface hardening?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Isotopic", "Anistopic", "Orthotopic", "Any of these"],
        correctAnswer: "Orthotopic",
        question: "Wood is an _________ material; that is, its mechanical properties are unique and independent in three mutually perpendicular directions-longitudinal, radial, and tangeltial.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["RC 35", "RC 80", "RC 60", "RC 50"],
        correctAnswer: "RC 60",
        question: "What is the largest roller chain size that can be used for power transmission at a sprocket speed of 1000 rpm?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["0.044", "0.022", "0.011", "0.033"],
        correctAnswer: "0.022",
        question: "In die casting accurate parts made of steel, what shrinkage allowance in inches per inch is recommended?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Tolerance", "Limit", "Deviation", "Allowance"],
        correctAnswer: "Deviation",
        question: "What is the algebraic difference between a size and the corresponding basic size?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["Facing", "Finishing", "Turning", "Blanking"],
        correctAnswer: "Blanking",
        question: "In manufacturing, this is the operation of cutting out flat area to some desired shape and is usually the first step in a series of operation.",
        topic: "NA"
    },
    {
        choices: ["0.80", "0.70", "0.75", "1.0"],
        correctAnswer: "0.70",
        question: "In estimating the actual endurance strength of steel parts, one of the factors to be considered is the material factor, which of the following is the recommended material factor for cast steel?",
        topic: "NA"
    },
]